<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="app_name">michigan.mahjong</string>
	<string name="ek_img_content">ExportKit Image</string>
	<string name="mahjong_ai_string">Mahjong AI</string>
	<string name="text_string">Guidebook</string>
	<string name="text_ek1_string">Get Started</string>
	<string name="rule_intro">
		Welcome player! You never played Mahjong before?
		You are experienced but need a refresher?
		This guidebook can help you through!</string>
	<string name="rule_tiles">
		Mahjong consists of 34 different tiles.
		 For each tile, there are 4 of them, so there are a total of 136 tiles.
		 They belong to 5 groups: Man, Pin, Sou, Wind and Dragon.
		 Man, Pin, and Sou each have 9 distinct tiles in their suit, numbered 1 through 9.
		 Wind has 4 distinct tiles in its suit classified as North, East, South, and West
		 and Dragon has 3 distinct tiles in its suit classified as Red, Green and White.
		 The 7 Wind and Dragon together are known as Honors.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_basic">
		When a game starts, a player will have 13 tiles in hand that are hidden to other players.
		 Every time it is your turn, you will draw a tile, making your hand total 14 tiles.
		 You will then have to one of the 14 tiles into the discard pile. This process allows
		 you to change the composition of the tiles in your hand.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_win">
		In order to win a round of the game, you must get a winning hand. You get a winning hand
		 when the 14 tiles you consists of sequences, triplets, and pairs. When you have 13 tiles
		 and only need one more tile to win, your hand is called Tenpai (Ready Hand).
		 Additionally, a winning hand must have a Yaku, which is a specific condition for tile
		 patterns your Tenpai and winning hand must meet.
		\n\n
		Pairs are a set of two identical tiles. Triples are a set of three identical tiles.
		 Sequences are a set of three consecutive tiles from the same group. Usually,
		 you win when your hand consists of four sequences or triplets and a pair.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_tanyao">
		Tanyao means you must not hold any Terminal tiles or Honor tiles in your hand.
		 Terminal tiles are tiles 1 and 9 of the Man, Pin, and Sou groups and Honor tiles
		 are from the Wind and Dragon groups.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_yakuhai">
		Yakuhai refers to having one of the following Triplets:
		Dragon Tiles, Prevalent Wind and Seat Wind.\n\n
		Having a triplet of Red, Green or White can be used as Yaku.
		At the beginning of each round, a wind is assigned to the round and each player.
		Prevalent Wind is three Wind tiles from the current wind type of the round,
		East Wind for East Round, South Wind for South Round, and West Wind for West Round.
		Similarly, Seat Wind is three Wind tiles from of own your player,
		East Wind for East Player, South Wind for South Player, West Wind for West Player,
		and North Wind for North Player.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_riichi">
		Riichi is the distinguishing part of this game and namesake mechanic.\n\n
		Riichi can be declared by a player when the player has Tenpai and at Menzenchin (Closed Hand),
		meaning that player did not steal any tiles (Chii, Pon, Kan). By declaring Riichi, a player
		cannot change the content of their hand with the exception of declaring certain closed quads.
		A player can also decide not to declare Riichi, in which case the player would continue
		playing as normal.\n\n
		When calling Riichi, a player must declare before discarding their tile, place 1000 points
		stick out, and turn the tile sideways when they discard. The player then continues on
		autopilot until picking up the winning tile. The advantages of Riichi is one Yaku,
		increasing the value of the hand and allows the winner to receive any 1000 point stick.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_advanced">
		There are 42 Yakus total and various other mechanics.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_open">
		Each player discards unwanted tiles to the discard pile. You can steal those discarded
		tiles in certain circumstances. Upon stealing a tile and forming a valid combination,
		the stolen tile and tiles from your hand that make the combination are open, meaning
		they are displayed out to the other players. Your hand is no longer Menzenchin.\n\n
		Chii is called to steal from the player who last discarded (player on your left)
		in order to form a valid Sequence with two tiles from your hand.\n\n
		Pon is called to complete a Triplet with two tiles in your hand. You can call
		Pon on any player that discards.\n\n
		Kan is called to complete a Quad, which is four identical tiles. You can call
		Kan when you have a Triplet in your hand on any player that discards and can also call
		Kan when you draw the fourth tile to complete an existing Triplet.\n\n
		Open tiles will be displayed with one tile turned sideways like such.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_furiten">
		When a player is in a state of Furiten, the player cannot declare a winning hand from
		another player\'s discards meaning the player in Furiten can only win from self drawn tiles.
		There are three Furiten states: Discard Furiten, Temporary Furiten, and Riichi Furiten.\n\n
		Discard Furiten occurs when a player discared any potential winning tiles from their
		current hand.\n\n
		Temporary Furiten occurs to a player for a turn if a winning tile was discarded and the
		player did not call it. Temporary Furiten ends after the player discards a tile.\n\n
		Riichi Furiten occurs when a player declares Riichi and does not call a potential winning
		tile that was discarded after declaration.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_tsumo">
		Tsumo refers to winning a hand by drawing the winning tile while the player has Menzenchin.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_pinfu">
		Pinfu refers to winning a hand with four Sequences and one non-Yakuhai Pair, with the
		potential winning tiles must be from the side of a Sequence, while the player has Menzenchin.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_ippatsu">
		Ippatsu refers to winning within one turn after declaring Riichi, and no draws or discards
		are interrupted by tile calls during that turn.
	</string>
</resources>