<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="app_name">michigan.mahjong</string>
	<string name="ek_img_content">ExportKit Image</string>
	<string name="mahjong_ai_string">Mahjong AI</string>
	<string name="text_string">Guidebook</string>
	<string name="text_ek1_string">Get Started</string>
	<string name="rule_intro">
		Welcome player! You never played Mahjong before?
		You are experienced but need a refresher?
		This guidebook can help you through!\n\n
		Mahjong is a tile-based game where players win various number of points
		from the tile combinations in their playing hand. The simplest way to win
		points is to win a round, but other combinations may also yield points.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_tiles">
		Mahjong consists of 34 different tiles.
		 For each tile, there are 4 of them, so there are a total of 136 tiles.
		 They belong to 5 groups: Man, Pin, Sou, Wind and Dragon.
		 Man, Pin, and Sou each have 9 distinct tiles in their suit, numbered 1 through 9.
		 Wind has 4 distinct tiles in its suit classified as North, East, South, and West
		 and Dragon has 3 distinct tiles in its suit classified as Red, Green and White.
		 The 7 Wind and Dragon together are known as Honors.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_basic">
		When a game starts, a player will have 13 tiles in hand that are hidden to other players.
		 Every time it is your turn, you will draw a tile, making your hand total 14 tiles.
		 You will then have to one of the 14 tiles into the discard pile. This process allows
		 you to change the composition of the tiles in your hand.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_win">
		In order to win a round of the game, you must get a winning hand. You get a winning hand
		 when the 14 tiles you consists of sequences, triplets, and pairs. When you have 13 tiles
		 and only need one more tile to win, your hand is called Tenpai (Ready Hand).
		 Additionally, a winning hand must have a Yaku, which is a specific condition for tile
		 patterns your Tenpai and winning hand must meet.
		\n\n
		Pairs are a set of two identical tiles. Triples (Koutsu) are a set of three identical tiles.
		 Sequences (Shuntsu) are a set of three consecutive tiles from the same group. Usually,
		 you win when your hand consists of four sequences or triplets and a pair.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_tanyao">
		Tanyao means you must not hold any Terminal tiles or Honor tiles in your hand.
		 Terminal tiles are tiles 1 and 9 of the Man, Pin, and Sou groups and Honor tiles
		 are from the Wind and Dragon groups.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_yakuhai">
		Yakuhai refers to having one of the following Triplets:
		Dragon Tiles, Prevalent Wind and Seat Wind.\n\n
		Having a triplet of Red, Green or White can be used as Yaku.
		At the beginning of each round, a wind is assigned to the round and each player.
		Prevalent Wind is three Wind tiles from the current wind type of the round,
		East Wind for East Round, South Wind for South Round, and West Wind for West Round.
		Similarly, Seat Wind is three Wind tiles from of own your player,
		East Wind for East Player, South Wind for South Player, West Wind for West Player,
		and North Wind for North Player.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_riichi">
		Riichi is the distinguishing part of this game and namesake mechanic.\n\n
		Riichi can be declared by a player when the player has Tenpai and at Menzenchin (Closed Hand),
		meaning that player did not steal any tiles (Chii, Pon, Kan). By declaring Riichi, a player
		cannot change the content of their hand with the exception of declaring certain closed quads.
		A player can also decide not to declare Riichi, in which case the player would continue
		playing as normal.\n\n
		When calling Riichi, a player must declare before discarding their tile, place 1000 points
		stick out, and turn the tile sideways when they discard. The player then continues on
		autopilot until picking up the winning tile. The advantages of Riichi is one Yaku,
		increasing the value of the hand and allows the winner to receive any 1000 point stick.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_advanced">
		There are 42 Yakus total and various other mechanics. The next section will cover several
		mechanics you may encounter, followed by a list of Yakus.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_open">
		Each player discards unwanted tiles to the discard pile. You can steal those discarded
		tiles in certain circumstances. Upon stealing a tile and forming a valid combination,
		the stolen tile and tiles from your hand that make the combination are open, meaning
		they are displayed out to the other players. Your hand is no longer Menzenchin.\n\n
		Chii is called to steal from the player who last discarded (player on your left)
		in order to form a valid Sequence with two tiles from your hand.\n\n
		Pon is called to complete a Triplet with two tiles in your hand. You can call
		Pon on any player that discards.\n\n
		Kan is called to complete a Quad, which is four identical tiles. You can call
		Kan when you have a Triplet in your hand on any player that discards and can also call
		Kan when you draw the fourth tile to complete an existing Triplet.\n\n
		Open tiles will be displayed with one tile turned sideways like such.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_furiten">
		When a player is in a state of Furiten, the player cannot declare a winning hand from
		another player\'s discards meaning the player in Furiten can only win from self drawn tiles.
		There are three Furiten states: Discard Furiten, Temporary Furiten, and Riichi Furiten.\n\n
		Discard Furiten occurs when a player discared any potential winning tiles from their
		current hand.\n\n
		Temporary Furiten occurs to a player for a turn if a winning tile was discarded and the
		player did not call it. Temporary Furiten ends after the player discards a tile.\n\n
		Riichi Furiten occurs when a player declares Riichi and does not call a potential winning
		tile that was discarded after declaration.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_draw">
		There is a possibility that the round ends in a draw, where no player wins.\n\n
		Four-Wind Discard - When each player discards the same Wind Tile in the first turn.\n\n
		Four-Kan Abortion - When two or more players called for a total of four Quads.\n\n
		Four-Player Riichi - When all four players declare Riichi.\n\n
		Nine different Terminals and Honors - If you hand consists of nine different terminal and
		honor tiles, you have the option to declare a draw in your first turn before any tiles
		are called.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_yaku_overview">
		Yakus can be separated into several different categories which yield a different number of
		points. These are 1-Han, 2-Han, 3-Han, 6-Han, Mangan, and Yakuman. The three basic
		Yakus covered earlier, Riichi, Yakuhai, and Tanyao all fall under 1-Han.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_1han">
		Riichi - refers to winning a hand after achieving Tenpai while having Menzenchin.\n\n
		Tanyao - All Simples - refers to winning without Yaochuu (terminal or honor tiles).\n\n
		Tsumo -  refers to winning a hand by drawing the winning tile while the player has Menzenchin.\n\n
		Yakuhai - refers to winning with a triplet of Player wind, Round wind, or Dragon tiles.\n\n
		Pinfu - One Shot - refers to winning a hand with four Sequences and one non-Yakuhai Pair,
		with the potential winning tiles must be from the side of a Sequence, while the player
		has Menzenchin.\n\n
		Iipeikou - Pure Double Sequence - refers to winning a hand with two identical sequences.\n\n
		Ron - refers to winning on another player\'s Kan. Also called Robbing a Kan. Additional
		condition is when you have a Tenpai for thirteen orphans, you can call on a closed Kan.
		Rinshan Kaihou - After a Kan - refers to winning a hand with the tile drawn from the
		Dead Wall after immediately calling a Kan.\n\n
		Haitei Raoyue - Under the Sea - refers to winning with Tsumo on the last drawable tile
		from the live wall.\n\n
		Houtei Raoyui - Under the River - refers to winning on the last discarded tile by
		calling Ron.\n\n
		Ippatsu - One-shot - refers to winning within one turn after declaring Riichi, and
		no draws or discards are interrupted by tile calls during that turn.\n\n
	</string>
	<string name="rule_2han">
		Double Riichi - declare Riichi with your starting hand before any tiles are called.\n\n
		Sanshoku Doukou - Triple Triplets - win with three identically numbered triplets
		across the three suits.\n\n
		Sankantsu - Three Quads - win with three quads, which are considered as triplets
		plus one extra.\n\n
		Toitoi - All Triplets - win with all (four) triplets or quads.\n\n
		Sanankou - Three Concealed Triplets - Win with three closed triplets.\n\n
		Shousangen - Little Three Dragons - Win a hand with two triplets out of the three
		Dragon Tiles, plus a pair of the third dragon tile.\n\n
		Honroutou - All Terminals and Honors - Win with only honor and terminal groups.\n\n
		Chiitoi	- Seven Pairs - Win a hand with seven different pairs, only while Menzenchin.\n\n
		Chanta - Half Outside Hand - Win a hand where every tile group with an honor or terminal.
		2 Han Closed/1 Han Open.\n\n
		Ittsuu - Pure Straight - Win a hand with a complete string of 1-9 tile,
		use sequences of the same suit. 2 Han Closed/1 Han Open.\n\n
		Sanshoku Doujun - Mixed Triple Sequence - Win with three identically numbered sequences
		across the three different suits. 2 Han Closed/1 Han Open.\n\n
	</string>
	<string name="rule_3han">
		Ryanpeikou - Twice Pure Double Sequence - win with two-identical sequences two times.\n\n
		Junchan - Fully Outside Hand - win with every tile group (Sequence, Triplet, Pair)
		with a terminal. 3 Han Closed/2 Han Open.\n\n
		Honitsu - Half Flush - Win with Honor tiles and with only one suit of numbered tiles.
		3 Han Closed/2 Han Open.
	</string>
	<string name="rule_6han">
		Chinitsu - Full Flush - Win a hand where all tiles are from the same numbered suit.
		6 Han Closed/5 Han Open.\n
	</string>
	<string name="rule_mangan">
		Nagashi Mangan - Mangan at Draw - win a game with all your discarded tiles being
		Terminal Tiles and no one has called them.\n
	</string>
	<string name="rule_yakuman">
		Tenhou - Blessing of Heaven - Win a hand by Tsumo as a dealer in the first turn
		with the first draw.\n\n
		Chiihou - Blessing of Earth - Win a hand by Tsumo as a non-dealer in the first turn
		before any tiles are called.\n\n
		Daisangen - Big Three Dragons - Win a hand with three triplets or quads of all the
		three Dragon Tiles. Either Hand open or closed.\n\n
		Suuankou - Four Concealed Triplets - Win a hand with four closed Triplets.
		A Tanki wait for Suuankou is considered a Double Yakuman.\n\n
		Tsuuiisou - All Honors - Win a hand that consists entirely of honor tiles.\n\n
		Ryuuiisou - All Green - Win a hand that consists of any four tile groups and
		a pair that consists of only 2, 3, 4, 6, 8 of souzu and/or the green dragon tiles.
		Literally, this hand is composed of "all green" painted tiles.\n\n
		Chinroutou - All Terminals - win a hand with every tile being a terminal.
		No other tile type are used: no simples (2-8) or honors.\n\n
		Kokushi Musou - Thirteen Orphans - win a hand with of one of each terminal tile from
		each suit and one of each of the honor tiles. The 14th tile must be a duplicate of
		any terminal or honor tile. A 13-wait kokushi (waiting for any terminal/honor) is
		considered a Double Yakuman.\n\n
		Shousuushi - Four Little Winds - Win a hand that requires three groups (Triplets or Quads)
		of winds, and a pair of the last wind.\n\n
		Daisuushi - Four Big Winds - Win a hand that requires groups of all four winds. Double Yakuman.
		Suukantsu - Four Quads - Win a hand with four quads. Requires the hand has collected
		kan four times.\n\n
		Chuuren Poutou - Nine Gates - win a hand that contains the 13-tile pattern
		1-1-1-2-3-4-5-6-7-8-9-9-9 of the same suit, plus any one more tile from the suit.
		A 13 sided wait True Nine Gates is worth Double Yakuman.\n
	</string>
	<string name="rule_dora">
		Another feature to earn points is Dora.
		There are dead wall tiles present at the beginning of the game. At the start, one of the
		tiles from the dead wall is placed faced up. That tile is called the Dora indicator.
		A tile that is the next in the same suit (where terminals loop to the beginning) is worth
		one Han per tile. Also, in Japanese Mahjong, there are red dora which is an extra Han.
		Ura-dora is when winning using Riichi, the rest of the tiles in dead wall can be used
		as Dora indicators.
	</string>
</resources>